Darlington Hoopes papers, 1910-1977 01883
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
Darlington Hoopes papers
1910-1977
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
01883
15 Linear Feet
Darlington Hoopes (1896-1989) was a lawyer and Socialist Party official from Reading, Pennsylvania. Hoopes served as a member of the Pennsylvania House of Representatives from 1930 to 1936, and later ran for Vice-President and President as a Socialist Party candidate. This collection contains materials that document Hoopes activism, his political career, and his work as a Socialist Party official.
Collection Overview
The Darlington Hoopes papers consist of materials that document Hoopes activism, his political career, and his work as a Socialist Party official for the Socialist Party (U.S.) (1917-1977), the Socialist Party of Pennsylvania (1920-1952), and the Local Berks Country Socialist Party of Pennsylvania (1910-1975). Political materials include legislative bills introduced as Hoopes as a member of the Pennsylvania House of Representatives; campaign records for his vice-presidential (1944) and presidential campaigns (1952, 1956); correspondence and minutes of the National Executive Committee and the Young People's Socialist League; Socialist newsletters; and press clippings. Some potential areas of interest include correspondence and administrative records concering civil rights, equality before the law, fair housing rights, and discrimination in housing for Reading, Pennsylvania; as well as correspondence and photographs from a German prisoner of war held in the Soviet Union during World War II.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Darlington Hoopes (1896-1989) was a lawyer and Socialist Party official from Reading, Pennsylvania. Hoopes served as a member of the Pennsylvania House of Representatives from 1930 to 1936. In 1944 Hoopes was the Socialist Party's Vice Presidential candidate, sharing the ticket with presidential candidate Norman Thomas. Hoopes was also the Social Party's Presidential candidate in 1952 and 1956.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged to the following series: Socialist Party (U.S.); Socialist Party of Pennsylvania; Local Berks County, Socialist Party of Pennsylvania (Reading, Pa.); Eastern Cooperative League; Pennsylvania Equal Rights Council; Reading-Berks (Pa.) Human Relations Council; microfilm.
Socialism -- United States -- History -- 20th century
- Socialist Party (U.S.), 1917-1977; 1
  - Correspondence; Socialist newsletters, including Hammer & Tongs; political campaign bulletins, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Regional Socialist newsletters, including: California socialist; Colorado call; Florida socialist; North West call; Socialist spotlight; and Tennessee Valley Socialist, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Constitution of the Socialist Party of the United States of America, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Norman Thomas testimonial luncheon (Commodore Hotel, New York), programs and clippings, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence; minutes (administrative records); Socialist newsletters, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - Oath at the Elbe, signed by Joseph Polowsky, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sketch of Léon Blum, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and photographs from a German prisoner of war held in the Soviet Union after the Battle of Stalingrad (Volgograd, Russia), 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National Chairman's correspondence; Young People's Socialist League minutes (administrative records) and reports, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - National Chairman's correspondence; National Executive Committee minutes (administrative records); flier protesting the legal lynching of the Groveland Four (Lake County, Florida), 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Regional Socialist newsletters (Hollywood Red Ink; The Roberts News); California pension plan pamphlets, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Conference proceedings; correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 4-14)
  - Socialist Party - Social Democratic Federation, Unity Convention (New York): correspondence; statement, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Prohibition Party National Committee: correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    General
    Original folder contents were photocopied and removed from the collection due to water damage and mildew.
  - Clippings; correspondence, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - National Executive Committee: brochures; correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 5-12)
  - National Executive Committee: brochures; correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1948-1953 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Young People's Socialist League minutes (administrative records) and reports, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - National Executive Committee minutes (administrative records); Young People's Socialist League minutes (administrative records) and reports, 1948-1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - National Executive Committee: clippings; correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 16-18)
  - National Executive Committee: correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1943-1949 (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
  - Socialist nomination papers, 1928-1936 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Clippings and correspondence regarding speeches and speaking commitments, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Executive Committee: clippings; correspondence; minutes (administrative records); Young People's Socialist League minutes (administrative records) and reports, 1922-1935 (Box 7, Folder 1-16)
  - National Executive Committee: organization leaflets (printed works), 1917, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Norman Thomas political campaign: correspondence; leaflets; speeches by Norman Thomas, 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Norman Thomas and Darlington Hoopes political campaign: National Executive Committee correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Norman Thomas and Darlington Hoopes political campaign: clippings; correspondence; radio broadcast speeches, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - General election independent nominating petition of the Socialist Party, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Harold E. Fackert relating to pacifism; including drawings copied from The Jersey journal and Jersey observer (Human goodwill; Tears of the Korean people; War battered Europe; Children of Nagasaki), 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 27th National Convention (Detroit, Michigan) reports, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Darlington Hoopes and Samuel H. Friedman political campaign: clippings; correspondence, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
  - Election clippings, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Darlington Hoopes and Samuel H. Friedman political campaign: speeches, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Darlington Hoopes and Samuel H. Friedman political campaign: clippings; correspondence; speeches, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Social Democratic Federation: brochures; correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 16-19)
  - Social Democratic Federation: National convention (Chicago, Illinois) proceedings; correspondence, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Socialist newsletter, Hammer & Tongs, 1958, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Election clippings and pamphlets, 1937-1950 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Socialist Labor Party of America: brochures; pamphlets, 1931-1940 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Socialist Labor Party of America: membership packet, Parti Socialiste (France) SFIO, 1932-1934 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, speeches, 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Social Democratic Federation: National Executive Committee: articles of incorporation; correspondence (including with Algernon Lee); minutes (administrative records), 1938-1946 (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
  - National convention (Chicago, Illinois) proceedings; minutes (administrative records); Socialist newsletter, Hammer & Tongs; Young People's Socialist League minutes (administrative records) and reports, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - National convention (Commodore Hotel, New York) clippings, correspondence and proceedings; Socialist newsletter, Hammer & Tongs, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - National Action Committee: correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1962-1972 (Box 11, Folder 7-14)
  - Union for Democratic Socialism: correspondence, newsletters, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; minutes (administrative records); Socialist newsletters, including Hammer & Tongs, 1967-1974 (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
  - National Action Committee: correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 8-11)
  - Socialist newsletters, including: Colorado call; Hammer & Tongs; North West call; Philadelphia Observer; Socialist spotlight, 1966-1975 (Box 13, Folder 12-14)
  - Correspondence concerning bequests, 1963-1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Social Democratic Federation: brochures; correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
  - National Action Committee: correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1959-1960 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, election clippings and memorandums, circa 1955 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Social Democratic Federation: brochures; correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
  - National Executive Committee correspondence; Socialist newsletters, including Share Croppers' Voice (Southern Tenant Farmers' Union), 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 12-17)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 14, Folder 18-20)
- Socialist Party of Pennsylvania, 1920-1952; 2
  - Pennsylvania State Executive Committee: correspondence; financial statements; minutes (administrative records), 1920-1932 (Box 3, Folder 9-13)
  - Pennsylvania State Executive Committee: correspondence; financial statements; minutes (administrative records), 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Membership lists, 1930-1934 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Membership lists, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania State Executive Committee: correspondence; financial statements; minutes (administrative records), 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Bulletins; clippings; correspondence; illustrated flier protesting the political ignorance and prejudice of the American economic circus, 1932-1942 (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1937 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
  - Bills (legislative records) introduced by Hoopes to the Pennsylvania General Assembly, House of Representatives, 1931-1936 (Box 8, Folder 6-13)
- Local Berks County, Socialist Party of Pennsylvania (Reading, Pennsylvania), 1910-1975; 3
  - Economic Opportunity Council of Reading and Berks County, Pennsylvania: correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5-10)
  - Economic Opportunity Council of Reading and Berks County, Pennsylvania: Housing Subcommittee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters: Economic Opportunity Report; NACD News (National Association for Community Development), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Economic Opportunity Council of Reading and Berks County, Pennsylvania: clippings, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Economic Opportunity Council of Reading and Berks County, Pennsylvania: lease agreement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reading, Pennsylvania Consumers Cooperative Association: articles of incorporation; bylaws and minutes (administrative records); correspondence, 1945-1952 (Box 3, Folder 4-8)
  - Pennsylvania Black News, 1935 August 30 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Reading Labor Advocate (Reading, Pa.), 1934 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Berks Patriot (Reading, Pa.), 1939 September (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Publications (including: Communist Manifesto; pamphlets by Norman Thomas; political poster featuring Hoopes and J. Henry Stump; Socialist Campaign Bulletin) and photograph of J. Henry Stump, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Pension brochures: 60 After 60 Committee (Reading, Pa.), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clippings; correspondence; minutes (administrative records); publications, including: Berks County Democrat (Reading, Pa.), 1943-1952 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings; correspondence; petitions; publications, including: The Pioneer (Reading, Pa.), 1930-1936 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence; speeches and educational radio broadcast announcements, 1938-1951 (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence; publications; speeches, 1942-1951 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence regarding speeches and speaking commitments, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; speeches and educational radio broadcast announcements, 1929-1951 (Box 6, Folder 16-19)
  - Clippings, correspondence, 1910-1935 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
  - Minutes (administrative records), 1936 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1922-1927 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Young People's Socialist League: constitution; correspondence; illustrated leaflets, 1932-1935 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, correspondence, minutes (administrative records), 1933-1946 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - The Pioneer (Reading, Pa.), 1931-1940 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - Labor forums and symposia (conferences): correspondence, financial statements, programs, 1966-1969 (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Clippings; minutes (administrative records), 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 15-16)
  - The Reading Socialist; local brochures, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Socialist Party of Reading, Pennsylvania, correspondence and dissertation by William Pratt, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Eastern Cooperative League, 1941-1951; 4
  - Correspondence; financial statements; minutes (administrative records); pamphlets, 1941-1948 (Box 2, Folder 9-15)
  - Correspondence; financial statements; minutes (administrative records); newsletters and pamphlets, including: The Cooperator, 1945-1951 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Board and membership policy actions, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Annual reports; correspondence; financial and operating statements, 1946-1951 (Box 10, Folder 9-16)
  - Correspondence; minutes (administrative records), 1946-1951 (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
- Pennsylvania Equal Rights Council, 1961-1968; 5
  - Correspondence and press releases concerning civil rights in Pennsylvania, 1964-1968 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence and press releases concerning civil rights in Pennsylvania, 1961-1963 (Box 13, Folder 16-18)
- Reading-Berks, Pennsylvania Human Relations Council, 1962-1974; 6
  - Human relations commission: clippings, correspondence and minutes (administrative records) concerning civil rights, equality before the law, fair housing rights and discrimination in housing, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 4-13)
  - Bulletins; clippings; press releases, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Microfilm, 7
  - Detailed microfilm reels index (Box 16)
  - Access copies (Box 15)
  - Positive originals (Box 15)